grandparents.com 2017-10-01

# Privacy Policy - Grandparents.com

**Updated July 10, 2014**

At Grandparents.com (“ ** _Company_** ,” “ ** _we_** ” or “ ** _us_** ”), your privacy is very important to us.  This privacy policy (“ ** _Policy_** ”) provides you with a description of the types of information we collect about you when you visit grandparents.com (including any subdomains, the “ ** _Site_** ”), and how we use that information.  By visiting or using the Site and/or using our online resources, tools and applications, you agree to our [Terms of Service](http://www.grandparents.com/terms-of-service) and this Policy.  If you do not agree to this Policy, please do not use or access the Site.

###  This Policy applies only to information we collect through the Site and not to information collected offline.  For more information on how the Site may redirect you to other web sites, please see the “Links and Redirection to Third Party Sites” section below.

**Table of Contents** **:   **

  * _**Information We Collect**_
  * _**How We Use Information; Joining Our Community**_
  * _**Who We Share Your Personal Information With**_
  * _**Service Providers and Partners**_
  * _**Credit Card Processor**_
  * _**Legal Processes; Your Agent or Guardian**_
  * _**A Company That Purchases or Merges with Us**_
  * _**Use and Sharing of Aggregate Information**_
  * _**Online Tracking; “Do Not Track” Signals**_
  * _**Account Security**_
  * _**Choice and Opt-Out**_
  * _**Updating Information**_
  * _**Links and Redirection to Third Party Sites**_
  * _**Children’s Privacy**_
  * _**Effective Date; Policy Changes**_
  * _**Governing Law; Your California Privacy Rights**_
  * _**Contact Us**_

###  _**Information We Collect**_

We collect and store information that you choose to provide to us as well as data related to how you use and visit the Site.

•  _Creating an Account_ \- Many features on the Site can be accessed without creating an account, but there are some activities (like participating in online chat rooms) that require you to register for a member account.  Creating a member account requires you to provide your name and email address, and to select a username and password.  We have two levels of membership, Basic (free) Membership and Premium Membership.  If you select Premium Membership, you will also need to provide a billing address, credit card information, gender and birth month and year.

•  _Completing your Profile_ \- Once you have created an account, you can choose to provide additional personal information that can be seen by other members of the Site when they click on your profile, including your age, location, birthdate, gender, photograph and a short bio.  Members can also see information about your use of the Site, such as the date on which you became a member, your active posts count, your profile views count and your membership title (e.g. newbie, member, advanced member).  Your user name and comments you make on the Site will always be viewable to other Site users, including non-members.

•  _Logging in Through Facebook_ \- If you have a Facebook account, you may log in using Facebook Connect, a Facebook, Inc., application that operates in connection with the Site.  We do not collect Facebook posts, photos or contacts or share Facebook log-in information with any third parties.  By electing to register and log in using your Facebook account, you permit the Site to access the email address and name associated with your Facebook account for purposes of verifying your identity.  This Privacy Policy applies to information collected by us through your Facebook Connect login; however, your activities on Facebook are covered by the Facebook privacy policy and other terms of use.

•  _Content You Upload to the Site_ \- Using your account, certain functions of the Site allow you to upload, submit, disclose and share information, data, text, software, music, sound, photographs, graphics, video, messages, products, services or other materials (“ ** _Content_** ”).  It is solely up to you whether you provide the information described above.  If you do provide such information, you are consenting to the use of that information in accordance with the policies and practices described in this Policy.

•  _Data We Automatically Collect_ \- During your visit we automatically collect aggregate information and analytical data related to your Site visit.  Aggregate information is non-personally identifiable or anonymous information about you such as your IP address and your site visit history.  **Please see the section titled “ _Use and Sharing of Aggregate Information_ ” below for information regarding third parties that we share this type of information with and who are allowed to collect this type of information about you directly when you use the Site.**    

###  **_How We Use Information; Joining Our Community_**

We use the information we collect from you to manage the Site, resolve problems and respond to questions.  When you create an account, we _automatically_ enroll you in the American Grandparents Association (“ ** _AGA_** ”).  As a member of the AGA, you will receive email newsletters about products or services that we think will interest you, have access to coupons and deals, and are able to join online forums provided by the Site that allow you to connect with other grandparents.  For more information on the AGA, [click here](http://www.grandparents.com/american-grandparents-association).  Please see the section titled “Choice and Opt-Out” below for information on how to unsubscribe from our mailings or marketing materials.

When you upload Content to the Site, we may choose to publish or display that Content (together with your username) on the Site and in materials related to the Site and our products and services (including our advertising and marketing materials).  Published Content can be viewed by other Site visitors.  Please review the section titled “User Submissions and Content” in our Terms of Service for additional information regarding your obligations and promises you make when you provide Content to the Site.

###  _**Who We Share Your Personal Information With**_

•  _Service Providers and Partners_ – Depending on the preferences you select when registering for an account, we may share your account and profile information with our service providers who help us manage the Site and market our products or services.  In addition, if you opt-in to receiving marketing emails, we share information such as your name, email address, location, age, birthday and gender with certain trusted third parties so that they can contact you directly to market or sell their products and services. 

•  _Credit Card Processor_ \- We use a third-party credit card processor to process credit card payments for Premium Memberships.  Your name, billing address, and order total are securely shared with this payment processor so that they can complete your order.  Your credit card information (including your credit card number, the expiration date, and the security code on the back of your credit card) is securely transmitted to our credit card processor and stored by the credit card processor and not by us. 

•  _Legal Processes; Your Agent or Guardian_ \- We may disclose information to third parties in response to a subpoena, warrant, court order, or other similar legal process.  If a subpoena requests information about a user, we’ll make (if permitted) reasonable business efforts to contact that user before providing information to the party that requests it, but we cannot guarantee that we will be able to do so in all cases.  In addition, we disclose information that we believe is appropriate to cooperate in investigations of fraud or other illegal activity, or to investigate violations of our Terms of Service.  We may disclose information to your agent or legal representative (such as the holder of a power of attorney that you grant, or a guardian appointed for you).

•  _A Company That Purchases or Merges with Us_ \- As with any other business, it is possible that in the future we could merge with or be acquired by another company.  If an acquisition occurs, the successor entity would have access to the information we have collected, including customer account information, but would continue to be bound by this Policy unless and until it is amended.

###  _**Use and Sharing of Aggregate Information**_

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to collect data reflecting your use of the Site and may use such data for tracking, reporting and other activities in connection with our business.  “Cookies” are simple text files stored on your computer for use by a browser.  Certain Site features may only be available through the placement of cookies.  Cookies are a standard practice among Internet web sites, and most Internet browsers permit a user to accept, decline or delete cookies.  You will still be able to view the Site if you reject cookies, but your ability to use some Site features (such as automatically-generated recommendations) will be limited.  You will be unable to log into the Site if you reject cookies.  We are not limited in our use of your non-personal information that does not permit direct association with any specific individual, or non-identifiable aggregate information about our users (such as the number of users of the Site, where our users are located, or what features Site visitors use). 

This Site works with a first party cookie that collects anonymous traffic data at the Site.  We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate the Site and track whether you are logged into the Site during a particular visit.  In addition, we use persistent cookies to store how you came to the Site, recognize Site materials and Content you view and identify you automatically when you re-visit the Site.  A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.  You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file.

###  _**Online Tracking; “Do Not Track” Signals  **_

We contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors, help us improve our services, and show you relevant advertising both on and off the Site.  **_To accomplish this, we permit third parties to track our Site users over time and across web sites_**.  Our analytics partners, such as [QuantCast](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy), [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/), [comScore](http://www.comscore.com/About-comScore/Privacy-Policy) and [Compete](https://www.compete.com/about-compete/privacy/) help us understand how you arrived at the Site and what features of the Site you use.  Our advertising partners, including [Xaxis](http://www.xaxis.com/static/view/privacy-policy), [Adprime Media](http://www.adprimemedia.com/privacy/), [Advertising.com](http://advertising.aol.com/privacy), [Datonics](http://datonics.com/consumer-privacy-center/technology-privacy-policy), [Lijit](http://www.lijit.com/company/privacy-policy), [MediaCrossing](http://www.mediacrossing.com/privacy-policy/), [Conversant](http://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy), and [Google Adsense](http://www.google.com/adsense/start/), help determine what advertisements will be of greatest interest to you.  For example, we use cookies to learn whether Site members who saw an ad on the Site later visited the advertiser’s site and our partners use cookies to direct advertisements to you both on and off the Site.  In addition, we and our advertising partners use re-directing pixels to advertise products or services available on the Site that may interest you while you are visiting other web sites.  Cookies and ad technology such as web beacons, pixels, and anonymous ad network tags help us more effectively serve ads to you, as well as to collect aggregated data for our advertising partners. We have no access to or control over the cookies and tracking technologies used by our partners. 

These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on our site, other websites and other forms of media about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, check out <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

Some browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features.  Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the web sites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked.  Because there is not yet a common understanding of how to interpret the Do Not Track signal, we do not currently respond to Do Not Track signals on the Site.

###  _**Account Security**_

The security of your account relies on your protection of your user name and password.  You are responsible for maintaining the security of your user name and password and are solely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account.  You may not share your password or user name with anyone.  We will never ask you to send your password or other sensitive information to us in an email, though we may ask you to enter this type of information on the Site.  If you believe someone else has obtained access to your password, please change it immediately by logging in to your account on the Site and changing your Profile settings.  If you believe that an unauthorized access has already occurred please report it immediately at [help@grandparents.com](mailto:help@grandparents.com).

###  _Choice and Opt-Out_

You can choose to unsubscribe from marketing emails using the links contained in each marketing email you receive by following the instructions included in each email.  If you experience difficulty managing your notification settings or would like to opt-out of future mailings, you can contact us for help at [help@grandparents.com](mailto:help@grandparents.com).

###  _Updating Information_

You can review, correct, update or change your personal information on your account profile at any time.  Simply log into your account, go to your Profile, review your information and, if you wish, edit it with the options provided.  If you are unable to edit your information by logging into your account please contact us for help.

###  _**Links and Redirection to Third Party Sites**_

The Site includes links to third party websites (“ ** _Third Party Sites_** ”) where information, products or services that may be of interest to you can be located.  Third Party Sites include, among others, service providers who have a relationship with the Company.

Third Party Sites are not under our control, and we are not responsible for Third Party Sites or for their accuracy, sufficiency, correctness, reliability, veracity, completeness, or timeliness, any link contained therein, or any changes or updates to those sites.  The inclusion or access to Third Party Sites does not imply an endorsement by the Company, or of the provider’s content or services.  We reserve the right to terminate any link or linking program at any time.  Nonetheless, we try to protect the integrity of our Site and welcome any feedback about these Third Party Sites. 

Please be aware that when you enter a Third Party Site, any information you provide is subject to the terms of use and privacy policy of that Third Party Site.

###  _**Children’s Privacy**_

This Site and our services are not directed to persons under the age of 13.  If you become aware that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at [help@grandparents.com](mailto:help@grandparents.com).  We do not knowingly collect or solicit information from, market to or accept services from children.  If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child’s account.   

###  _**Effective Date; Policy Changes**_

Each time you use the Site, the current version of the Policy will apply.  When you use the Site, you should check the date of this Policy (which appears at the top of the Policy) and review any changes since the last version.  Our business changes frequently and this Policy is subject to change from time to time.  Unless stated otherwise, our current Policy applies to all information that we have about you.  We will not materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past or collect substantially more customer information than in the past without the consent of affected customers.

###  _**Governing Law; Your California Privacy Rights**_

This Policy is governed by the laws of the State of New York without giving effect to any principles of conflict of law.

**California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers who are California residents and who have provided the Company with “personal information” (as defined by Section 1798.83) to request certain information about the disclosure of that information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.   If you are a California resident with questions regarding this, please contact us via email at **[help@grandparents.com](mailto:help@grandparents.com)  **or by mail at the address listed in the “Contact Us” section below.**

###  _**Contact Us**_

If you have questions regarding this Policy, you may contact us using the information below.

Grandparents.com, Inc.

190 Farmington Avenue, Farmington, CT 06032

Phone: 646-839-8800

Email: [help@grandparents.com](mailto:help@grandparents.com)

_**Please also visit our[Terms of Service](http://www.grandparents.com/terms-of-service) establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our Site.**_
